Charles Ruas Papers, 1924-2020: Finding Aid C1372
Manuscripts Division
- Author and Artist Files, 1960-2020; 9 boxes
  - Young, Marguerite, circa 1960-1999; 5 boxes
    - Young, Marguerite, Harp Song for a Radical, Edited Draft of Part I: "Prelude in a Golden Key", circa 1994-1999; 3 folders (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
      Includes a full typescript of Part I, pages 1-383, along with a group of unedited cut pages at the end.
    - Young, Marguerite, Harp Song for a Radical: Edited Draft of Pages 558-1750, 1994-1999; 2 boxes
      Consists of a copy of an edited draft of pages 558-1750 of Marguerite Young's Harp Song for a Radical: The Life and Times of Eugene Victor Debs. The draft was written on a typewriter by Marguerite Young and annotated in her handwriting. This copy was collated during Young's last illness by her friends Dr. Marilyn Hamilton and Professor Suzanne Oboler and submitted to Knopf for publication after her death.
      - Young, Marguerite, Harp Song for a Radical: Edited Draft of Pages 558-1254, 1994-1999; 3 folders (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
      - Young, Marguerite, Harp Song for a Radical: Edited Draft of Pages 1255-1750, 1994-1999; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Young, Marguerite, Last Poems of Marguerite Young Drafts, 1993-1995; 3 folders (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
      Copies of typescript and manuscript drafts of an unpublished collection of later poems by Marguerite Young.
    - Young, Marguerite, Miss MacIntosh, My Darling, Chapter 1 and 2 Draft, circa 1960-1963; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Carbon copy of original typescript with handwritten corrections by Young and a note to Ruas on the first page.
    - Young, Marguerite, Correspondence and Photograph, 1986 October 27; 1 folder (Box 5, Folder 31)
      Includes correspondence with Paul Schullenberger from the MacArthur Fellows Program, regarding Marguerite Young's nomination for a MacArthur Fellowship. Includes a photograph of Marguerite Young holding the completed manuscript of Miss MacIntosh, My Darling.
    - Young, Marguerite, Publicity, 1995; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Memorial program with New York Times obituary.
  - Dust Jacket Proofs, 1980s; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes dust jacket proofs for Conversations with American Writers by Charles Ruas, Sketches from Life by Lewis Mumford, Sister Wolf and Group Sex by Ann Arensberg, and The Call: An American Missionary in China by John Hersey.
  - Postcards, 1977-2013; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Art Catalogues and Magazines, 1989-2012; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
    Includes catalogues for Musee Stendhal "L'affaire Berthet" (1989), Museo International delle Marionette Antonio Pasqualino, "Art on Edge" at Sezon Museum of Modern Art (Karizawa, Japan, 1991), "A View from the East" at Martyn Gregory Gallery (London, 2005-2006), "The Paintings of Gu Gan" at Goedhuis Gallery (New York, 2002), and Gallery & Studio magazine (New York, Vol. 10 No. 2, 2007-2008).
- Interviews, Radio, and Television, 1975-1984; 1975-2017; 6 boxes; 8 items; 291 digital files
  Arranged based on groupings in which materials were received.
  Consists of transcripts, audiocassettes, and CD-ROMs, and related materials documenting Charles Ruas's interviews with a variety of authors and cultural icons mainly throughout the 1970s and 1980s, although some recordings date to the mid 2000s. Ruas conducted interviews for broadcast on WBAI-FM radio, as well as for his 1985 book Conversations with American Writers. The transcripts of Ruas's interviews with Carlos Fuentes and Marguerite Young for The Paris Review are also here. Other authors represented within Ruas's interview materials include Toni Morrison, Buckminster Fuller, Michel Foucault, Eudora Welty, Truman Capote, Tennessee Williams, Norman Mailer, Mario Vargas Llosa, E. L. Doctorow, Susan Sontag, James Laughlin, William S. Burroughs, Donald Barthelme, and Joseph Heller, and others. In addition to interviews, some of the recordings document theatrical performances and readings, such as Anaïs Nin's reading of her introduction to Marguerite Young's Angel in the Forest. Interview transcripts often include multiple drafts and usually contain extensive corrections and editing, done in colored pencil, as well as Ruas's notes regarding his initial impressions of writers and their surroundings, which he often incorporated into the introductions of his published interviews. A group of CD-ROMs contain audio files from Ruas's interviews with artists for WPS1 Art Radio in the mid 2000s. Later additions include annotated program descriptions for Ruas's radio series, as well as a proposal for "Arts in New York: A Television Program" and recordings containing its trial program on artist Dan Flavin.
  - Interview Transcripts, 1975-1984; 2 boxes
    Transcripts are arranged alphabetically.
    - Arensberg, Ann, circa 1977-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Barthelme, Donald, 1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Capote, Truman, circa 1977-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Dahlberg, Edward, 1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Doctorow, E. L., 1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Edel, Leon, circa 1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Forman, Richard, 1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Foucault, Michel, 1983-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Includes the French transcript and Ruas's English translation, along with a letter from Ruas to Foucault regarding the interview.
    - Fuentes, Carlos ( The Paris Review), 1981; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Interviewed by Charles Ruas and Alfred MacAdam.
    - Fuller, Buckminster, circa 1975-1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Gardner, John, 1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Heyerdahl, Thor, circa 1976-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Kingston, Maxine Hong, circa 1976-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Kosiński, Jerzy, circa 1976-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Laughlin, James, 1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Interviewed by Charles Ruas and Susan Howe.
    - Mailer, Norman, circa 1983-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Morrison, Toni, 1981; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Nicolson, Nigel, 1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Sontag, Susan, circa 1982-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Stone, Robert, 1981; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Theroux, Paul, 1980; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Vargas Llosa, Mario, 1982; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Young, Marguerite ( The Paris Review), 1976; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Warhol, Andy, and Bob Colacello, circa 1980-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Welty, Eudora, circa 1977-1984; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Williams, Tennessee, 1975; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "The Struggle Against Censorship", 1974; 1 folder (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Transcript of a round table discussion with Maurice Girodias, William Burroughs, Allen Ginsberg, Carl Solomon, and James Grauerholz.
    - Conversations with American Writers, 1984-1985; 3 folders (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
      AM 2020-39
      Includes a full draft of the book called "Writers: Lives and Work," including transcripts of interviews.
  - Interview Recordings, 1975-1984; 1975-2005; 1 box 59 audiocassette tapes and 23 CD-ROMs
    Recordings are arranged alphabetically.
    - Arensberg, Ann, circa 1977-1984; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Barthelme, Donald, 1976; 1 box 3 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Burroughs, William: Naked Lunch, 1975; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Burroughs, William, and Allen Ginsberg: The Yage Letters, 1975; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Capote, Truman, circa 1977-1984; 1 box 3 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Dahlberg, Edward, 1975; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Doctorow, E. L.: Ragtime, 1976; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Foreman, Richard, 1975; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Foucault, Michel, 1983-1984; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      32101086137518_1_a.mp3
      32101086137518_2_a.mp3
      32101086137526_1_a.mp3
      32101086137526_2_a.mp3
    - Fuentes, Carlos, 1981; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Heller, Joseph, circa 1976-1984; 1 box 4 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Laughlin, James, 1976; 1 box 4 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Llosa, Mario Vargas, 1982; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Mabou Mines Performs 2 Samuel Beckett Plays, undated; 1 box 2 CD-ROMs (Box 4)
    - Mailer, Norman, circa 1983-1984; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Morrison, Toni, 1981; 1 box 7 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Nin, Anaïs: Introduction to Young's Angel In the Forest Reading, circa 1976; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Sanders, Ed: Miles of Beatnik Glory, circa 1975; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Seldes, Marian: "Image Inter Word," Reading of Miss MacIntosh, My Darling, 1976-1977; 1 box 3 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Settle, Mary Lee, undated; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Sontag, Susan, circa 1982-1984; 1 box 3 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Spackman, William, undated; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Theroux, Paul, 1980; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1984; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Welty, Eudora, circa 1977-1984; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
    - Williams, Tennessee, 1975; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Williams, Eric William, and Reid Whitmore on William Carlos Williams, circa 1976; 1 box 1 cassette tape (Box 4)
      Tape is marked "William Carlos Williams."
    - Young, Marguerite: Image Inter Word, 1976-1977; 1 box 2 cassette tapes (Box 4)
    - Young, Marguerite: Taped at Pennyfeathers Loud Noise, circa 1976-1977; 1 box 3 cassettes (Box 4)
    - WPS1 Conversations with Writers: From the Archives of Charles Ruas, 2005; 1 box 21 CD-ROMs (Box 4)
      Includes interviews with David Shipler, Walter Abish, Fanny Howe, Anne Waldman, Edwidge Danticat, Jessica Hagedorn, A. S. Byatt, Wang Ping, Lawrence Osborne, Robin Robertson, Lily Tuck, Patrick McGrath, Christopher Mason, Laura Flanders, Carol Brightman, Ron Padgett, Mary Dearborn, Karole P. B. Vail, Jean Nathan on Dare Wright, Barbara Goldsmith, Pascale Casanova, and Vestal McIntyre, hosted by Charles Ruas for WPS1, an art radio station run by the Museum of Modern Art's PS1.
  - WBAI Arts Production Dossier, 1974-1976; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Consists of a dossier outlining arts coverage implemented by Charles Ruas during the period from 1974-1976 at WBAI Pacifica Radio in New York and distributed to the Pacifica network of stations in Los Angeles, San Francisco, Houston, Washington, and Boston. During this period, these listener-sponsored stations were the voice of the counterculture, the protest against the Vietnam War, and the Civil Rights Movement. Programs listed and related photographs give an overview of the cultural landscape in New York City at the time.
  - WBAI Radio Program Descriptions and Publicity, 1970s; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Includes: The Reading Experiment, Miss Macintosh My Darling by Marguerite Young, in 35 parts; PR broadsheet for Arts Programs, November 1975; Drama & Theater Programs, March-June 1975; Drama program description; John Giorno Dial-A-Poem poets, 8 parts; Saturday Night Specials, fiction program descriptions; Dance program descriptions; Poetry program descriptions from live readings; Programs of Contemporary Writers; advertisement for the Last Days of Nablo Neruda, a documentary; Susan Howe poetry series; Paul Oppenheimer poetry series; Major American Writers series; William Burroughs advertisement for 4 programs; Jerzy Kosinski fiction series; Donald Barthelme fiction series; Art Programs, John Perrault series, Cindy Nemser, Judith Vivell.
  - Radio Program Descriptions, 2017; 1 box
    Consists of three sets of program descriptions, including a photograph and a "playbill" biography introducing each subject. Printouts from Clocktower website, with annotations by Ruas.
    - Historic Audio from the Archives of Charles Ruas Program Descriptions, 2017; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Conversations with Writers (PS1 MoMA Art on Air) Program Descriptions, 2017; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - The Reading Experiment (Marguerite Young: Miss Macintosh, My Darling) Program Descriptions, 2017; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Digital Audio Recordings and Programs, 1975-2015; 2016-2018; 291 digital files
    2019-97
    Consists of digitized and born-digital audio recordings and program descriptions for three radio series produced by Charles Ruas. This includes recordings from his "Conversations with Writers" series on PS1's radio program Art on Air, which later became Clocktower Radio. The "Conversations with Writers" recordings were digitally recorded in the studio from approximately 2010-2015. There are also recordings from the historic audio archives of Ruas's arts programming for WBAI-Pacifica, as well as the Reading Experiment, which contains all programs on Marguerite Young's Miss MacIntosh, My Darling. The "Historic WBAI" archives and "The Reading Experiment" were recorded on tape in the WBAI studios in NYC from 1975-1980. These programs were distributed nationally and deposited in the Pacifica Archives, but very few survived. The recordings were restored and digitized for Clocktower Radio by David Weinstein and Tennae Maki, who prepared them for broadcast and wrote the program descriptions. Program descriptions include those written by Ruas and his assistant, as well as screenshots of online program descriptions.
    - Conversations with Writers, 2018; 34 digital files
    - Program Descriptions, 2016-2019; 11 digital files
    - Ruas Historic WBAI, 2018-2019; 117 digital files
    - The Reading Experiment - Marguerite Young, 2018; 32 digital files
  - "Arts in New York: A Television Program", 1978; 2 boxes
    - "Arts in New York: A Television Program" Proposal, 1978; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Proposal by Marnie Mueller and Charles Ruas of WBAI Pacifica Radio in cooperation with WNYC-TV for a public television program focusing on the arts.
    - "In Daylight and Cool White", 1978; 1 folder 2 U-matic video tapes (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Consists of two video recordings containing the first trial program for "Arts in New York: A Television Program," the subject of which was minimalist artist Dan Flavin (1933-1996).
    - "Arts in New York" Application with Program Description and Budget, 1978; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Photographs, 1924-2019; 3 boxes; 2 digital files
  Consists of photographic prints, contact sheets, and negatives, primarily in black-and-white, including shots taken in the WBAI studio in New York City, as well as promotional photographs and portraits gifted to Ruas by authors and artists with whom he worked. Most of the photographs taken in the WBAI studio are by Joan Schwartz, including images of various authors reading from Marguerite Young's Miss MacIntosh, My Darling, as well as a number of photographs of poets reading at a New Year's Eve poetry reading at St. Mark's Church in-the-Bowery in 1975. In addition to containing photographs of many of the writers and artists reflected elsewhere throughout this collection, musicians and composers like Patti Smith, Lou Reed, and Phillip Glass are also represented in this group of photographs. Also of note is a group of portraits and photographs of performances by Babette Mangolte. While most photographic materials in the collection are described here, some, which were originally kept with manuscript materials and ephemera, are described with the general Author and Artist Files.
  Original file groups based on photographer were preserved. Other photographs are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Joan Schwartz WBAI Studio Contact Sheets and Negatives, 1974-1976; 1 box
    - Harry M. Koutoukas, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 6)
      3A-20A: Harry M. Koutoukas (playwright, performer) in WBAI recording studio, reading from Marguerite Young.
    - Alice Playten, Harry M. Koutoukas, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
      3A-14A: Alice Playten (stage actress), reading from Marguerite Young. 14A-20A: Harry Koutoukas in recording studio.
    - Alice Playten, Harry M. Koutoukas, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 8)
      2A-20A: Alice Playten in WBAI Pacifica studio. 21A-37A: Harry Koutoukas in studio.
    - Owen Dodson, Christopher Knowles, Robert Wilson, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 9)
      3A-26A: Owen Dodson reading from Marguerite Young's Miss MacIntosh, My Darling in studio. 27A-38A: Christopher Knowles (left) with Robert Wilson (right) in concert WBAI studio N.Y.
    - William Burroughs, Peter Zanger, Robert Wilson, Christopher Knowles, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 10)
      2A-5A; 18A-24A: William Burroughts reading from "Naked Lunch" in WBAI recording studio; William Burroughs (left) with Charles Ruas (standing right); Peter Zanger, recording engineer (sitting right). 7A-16A: Robert Wilson performing in studio. 6A-7A: Robert Wilson (left) Christopher Knowles (right). 11A-12A: Christopher Knowles performing in studio.
    - Wyatt Cooper, Dolores Brandon, Leo Lerman, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 11)
      2A-8A: Wyatt Cooper in studio reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling. 9A-11A, 16A-17A: Wyatt Cooper with actress Dolores Brandon, reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling. 23A-24A: Charles Ruas with Dolores Brandon in recording studio. 30A-37A: Leo Lerman reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling in WBAI studio.
    - Wyatt Cooper, Betty Lou Holland, Marian Seldes, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 12)
      3A-6A: Wyatt Cooper with Betty Lou Holland. 7A-16A: Betty Lou Holland reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling. 17A-20A: Marian Seldes reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling.
    - Marguerite Young, Honey Rovit, Frances Field, David Rapkin, Charles Potter, 1974; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 13)
      1A-2A: Marguerite Young. 3A: left to right, Honey Rovit, Frances Field, Marguerite Young, and student. 5A-10A: Charles Ruas settling Marguerite Young in recording studio. 11A-17A: Frances Field comforting Marguerite Young, Marguerite Young smoking in studio. 18A-22A: Marguerite Young (left) with Charles Ruas (right). 23A: David Rapkin, recording engineer. 24A: Marguerite Young. 25A-29A: Frances Field, David Rapkin, Marguerite Young, Charles Ruas, Honey Rovit in studio. 30A: Charles Potter, producer for WBAI Pacifica.
    - Anne Freemantle, Michael Higgins, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 14)
      1A-8A, 15A-30A: Anne Freemantle in recording studio. 9A-14A, 31A-37A: Michael Higgins in recording studio.
    - Michael Higgins, Anne Freemantle, Rob Wynne, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 15)
      5A-6A, 10A: Charles Ruas (left) with Michael Higgins (right) in recording studio. 21A-30A: Michael Higgins reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling. 11A-20A: Anne Freemantle. 31A-37A: Rob Wynne, artist, who scored the readings.
    - Tessa Kaner, Marian Seldes, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 16)
      8A-21A: Tessa Kaner. 22A-34A: Marian Seldes. Both are reading from Miss MacIntosh, My Darling.
    - Poetry Reading at St. Mark's on the Bowery, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 17)
      8-12A, 14-14A: William Burroughs. 3, 27-28, 30: Anne Waldman. 29: Maureen Owens. 5-5A: Michael Neuman. 32-35A: John Giorno reading. 13-13A: John Giorno and Anne Waldman. 16-20A, 25-25A: Patti Smith. Contact sheet only.
    - Richard Foreman "Journal of a Playwright" Rehearsal, 1976; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 18)
      From 1A to 36A.
    - Robert Wilson, Phillip Glass "Einstein on the Beach" Rehearsal, 1976; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 19)
      From 5A to 36A.
    - Halloween Party, WBAI Studio, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 20)
      Michael Neumann (jester), Marnie Mueller (program director), and Charles Ruas (arts director) in last picture with bow tie. Contact sheet only.
  - Babette Mangolte Photographs, 1971-1976; 1 box
    - Richard Foreman, 1971-1973; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 21)
      Includes a portrait of Foreman (1973) and photographs titled "Particle Theory" (1973) and "HcOh TiEnLa (or) Hotel China" (1971).
    - Phillip Glass, 1974-1976; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 22)
      Includes a photograph by Carol Mesereau of Phillip Glass (center) rehearsing "Einstein on the Beach" by Phillip Glass and Robert Wilson, and standing on right by column with neck scarf, David Warilow from Mabou Mines; and a 1974 and a 1976 portrait of Glass by Mangolte.
    - Vito Acconci, 1975; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 23)
      For "Radio Free America," WBAI.
    - Trisha Brown in Rehearsal, 1974; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Yvonne Rainer Performance, 1973-1976; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 25)
      Includes a photograph of Kate Parker in Yvonne Rainer's film "Kristina Talking Pictures" (1976); a photograph of "Projection #6: I am a stern and unrelenting judge..."; and photographs from "The Story of a Woman Who..." (1973), including Rainer sitting with John Erdman on the floor at her knees and a seascape projection, Rainer (right) and Erdman (left), and Rainer sitting (left) and Erdman sitting (right).
    - Meredith Monk Performance, 1974; 1 folder (Box 8, Folder 26)
      Meredith Monk, "Our Lady of Late", music for voice and glass (1972). Photo taken at the Salvatore Alla Gallery, Milan, Italy, in 1974.
  - John Ashbery, Self-Portrait in a Convex Mirror, 1975; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Photo credit: Jill Krementz.
  - Hommage à Bettina, 1990; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Program with photographs by Irving Penn for Photographie de mode, 1945-1955 (1990).
  - Elizabeth Bowen, 1981; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Photograph on promotional material by Knopf.
  - Ed Bowes, "Romance", 1975; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Karen Achenbach (left) Britta LeVa (right). Photograph of film "Romance" by Ed Bowes, for a performance at the Kitchen, 1974. Shown in performance of "Sexless: Half a Family," by Ed Bowes, WBAI, 1975. Photo credit: Ed. Bowes.
  - William Burroughs Negative by Joan Schwartz, 1975; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - John Cage, "Live Concert" Portrait, 1974; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Portrait for Live Concert. Photo credit: Dorothy Norman.
  - Virginia Carr, Carson McCullers, undated; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Portrait of Virginia Carr, author of The Lonely Hunter: A Biography of Carson McCullers, a biography of Carson McCullers (Photo credit: Al Alexander), along with an undated and uncredited portrait of Carson McCullers.
  - Laurie Colwin Photograph by Nancy Crampton, circa 1980s-1990s; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 14)
    2 copies.
  - Joseph Cornell, "La Marquise de la Rochejaquelein", 1943; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Catalog page with description and photograph of work.
  - Audrey Flack, Photorealism Paintings, 1976; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Photographs of paintings including 1) Jewelry on table, color (Photo credit: Bruce C. Jones); 2) Royal Flush, black and white (Photo credit: Bruce C. Jones); and 3) Smaller color print of Royal Flush (Photo credit: Louis K. Meisel Gal).
  - Anne Freemantle in Studio, 1975; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Two photographs by Joan Schwartz.
  - Carlos Fuentes Portrait, circa 1970s; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Photo credit: Jerry Bauer.
  - Jean Genet Photograph, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - John Giorno Meditating in Bunker on the Bowery, circa 1972-1975; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Photo credit: Peter Hujar. A copy of this photograph was made by the Poetry Society of America for their exhibition of contemporary poets.
  - John Giorno, Anne Waldman, and Jackie Curtis, St. Mark's New Year's Eve Poetry Reading, 1975; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Two photographs taken at St. Mark's Church, the Poetry Project's New Year's Eve Reading 1975. The first photograph is of John Giorno conferring with Anne Waldman. The second photograph is of John Giorno taking the stage with Jackie Curtis (poet, performer and playwright). Photo credit: Joan Schwartz.